<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xiwen514.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Differential expression analysis using DEseq2</title>
      <link>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-11-01-differential-expression-analysis-using-deseq2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-11-01-differential-expression-analysis-using-deseq2/</guid>
      <description>I borrow the data from this article ( https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.2008762117#data-availability) to analyze Alzheimer’s disease (AD) data, aiming to show the standard analysis during my work. The previous blog mainly focused on the quality control, dimensionality reduction, clustering, and cell type annotation of single-nuclei RNA seq data, and further analyzes the data for differential abundance analysis. Here, I apply DEseq2 for differential expression analysis to identify significant genes and explore their functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differential abundance analysis</title>
      <link>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-10-30-diff-abun-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-10-30-diff-abun-analysis/</guid>
      <description>I borrow the data from this article ( https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.2008762117#data-availability) to analyze Alzheimer’s disease (AD) data, aiming to show the standard analysis during my work. The previous blog mainly focused on the quality control, dimensionality reduction, clustering, and cell type annotation of single-nuclei RNA seq data. This blog further analyzes the data for differential abundance analysis.
Libraries # library(Seurat) library(dplyr) library(ggplot2) library(edgeR) Abundance visualization # seu &amp;lt;- readRDS(&amp;#34;../../../../../transcriptome_protein_AD_plat/sc_RNA/Seu_PCA_UMAP_annotated.RDS&amp;#34;) Seurat::DimPlot(seu, reduction=&amp;#34;umap&amp;#34;,label = TRUE)+NoLegend() Seurat::DimPlot(seu, reduction=&amp;#34;umap&amp;#34;, group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single nucleus analysis</title>
      <link>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-10-25-single-nucleus-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-10-25-single-nucleus-analysis/</guid>
      <description>I borrow the data from this article ( https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.2008762117#data-availability) to analyze Alzheimer’s disease (AD) data, aiming to show the standard analysis during my work. This report mainly analyze single nucleus RNA seq data of prefrontal cortex from 12 AD and 9 NC to identify differential signatures and explore these signatures&amp;rsquo; functions.
The data is prepossessed by Cell Ranger (version 3.0.1) with the default settings.
Libraries # library(Seurat) library(ggplot2) library(gridExtra) library(ggprism) library(SeuratObject) library(future) library(future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intergration of the platelet transcriptome and proteome in Alzheimer’s disease and aging data analysis</title>
      <link>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-10-23-multi-omics-intergration-of-the-platelet-in-alzheimer-s-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-10-23-multi-omics-intergration-of-the-platelet-in-alzheimer-s-disease/</guid>
      <description>I borrow the data from this article ( https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fmolb.2023.1196083/full ) to analyze Alzheimer’s disease (AD) data, aiming to show the standard analysis during my work. This report mainly integrate transccriptomes and proteomics data to identify a highly correlated multi-omics signature that discriminates AD and old group.
Load libraries # library(annotables) library(mixOmics) library(dplyr) library(DescTools) library(readxl) library(tibble) library(stringr) library(BiocParallel) library(tidyselect) Data preparation # Regarding the preprocessing, all of methods in mixOmics assume the right preprocessing method has been applied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The platelet transcriptome in Alzheimer’s disease and aging data analysis</title>
      <link>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-10-23-the-platelet-transcriptome-in-alzheimer-s-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-10-23-the-platelet-transcriptome-in-alzheimer-s-disease/</guid>
      <description>I borrow the data from this article ( https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fmolb.2023.1196083/full ) to analyze Alzheimer’s disease (AD) data, aiming to show the standard analysis during my work. This report mainly analyze Bulk RNA data by comparing AD VS old to identify differential genes and explore their functions.
This article provides DESeq2-normalized counts using Median of ratios method by 4 steps ( https://hbctraining.github.io/DGE_workshop/lessons/02_DGE_count_normalization.html):
creates a pseudo-reference sample (row-wise geometric mean) calculates ratio of each sample to the reference calculate the normalization factor for each sample (size factor) calculate the normalized count values using the normalization factor This data has 27 samples, 3 groups(AD, old and young), each group has 9 samples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The platelet proteome in Alzheimer’s disease and aging data analysis</title>
      <link>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-10-23-the-platelet-proteome-in-alzheimer-s-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-10-23-the-platelet-proteome-in-alzheimer-s-disease/</guid>
      <description>I borrow the data from this article ( https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fmolb.2023.1196083/full ) to analyze Alzheimer’s disease (AD) data, aiming to show the standard analysis during my work. This report mainly analyze proteomics data by comparing AD VS old to identify differential proteins and explore their functions.
Libraries # library(utils) library(PCAtools) library(factoextra) library(FactoMineR) library(parameters) library(tibble) library(ggplot2) library(ggvenn) library(skimr) library(dplyr) library(ggpubr) library(ggprism) library(VIM) library(ComplexHeatmap) library(EnhancedVolcano) library(clusterProfiler) library(gridExtra) # library(reactome.db) # library(ReactomePA) Proteomics data introduction # This article provides two proteomics data tables(AD and old, old and young) after MAXQUANT preprocessing, but without AD and young group protein abundance table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPPA data analysis</title>
      <link>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-09-29-rppa-data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-09-29-rppa-data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>What is RPPA? # Reverse phase protein array (RPPA) is a high-throughput antibody-based technique with the procedures similar to that of Western blots. Proteins are extracted from tumor tissue or cultured cells, denatured by SDS, printed on nitrocellulose-coated slides followed by antibody probe.
What are the advantages of RPPA? # Inexpensive, high-throughput method utilizing automation for increased quality and reliability Sample preparation requirements are similar to that of Western blots Complete assay requires only 40 microliters of each sample for 150 antibodies Robust quantification due to serial dilution of samples Here, I compare the differentially expressed genes based on the patients&amp;rsquo; status(aLive or dead) and their associated functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional analysis</title>
      <link>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-09-14-functional-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-09-14-functional-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Here mainly introduce over representation analysis(ORA), gene set enrichment analysis(GSEA) and gene set variation analysis(GSVA).
1. Over representation analysis(ORA) Hypergeometric test is a statistical method used to determine if the frequency of a specific subset in a sample significantly deviates from what would be expected under random sampling. To be specific, we classify the genes we’ve selected to see which ones have functions relevant to our research. Then, we conduct a test and use the p-value to determine if the association is random or significant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to PCA</title>
      <link>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-09-14-introduction-to-pca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-09-14-introduction-to-pca/</guid>
      <description>PCA is an unsupervised analysis that reflects the true trend of the data itself.
PCA is one of the dimension reduction methods.The purpose of PCA (Principal Component Analysis) is to transform the original data into a new coordinate system, where the variance of the data along the axes is maximized. The first principal component (PC1) represents the direction of the greatest variance in the data, while the second principal component (PC2) is orthogonal to PC1 and represents the direction of the second greatest variance, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
