<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>💜 Welcome to Sivan&#39;s blog! on Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://xiwen514.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 💜 Welcome to Sivan&#39;s blog! on Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xiwen514.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RPPA data analysis</title>
      <link>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-09-29-rppa-data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-09-29-rppa-data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>What is RPPA? # Reverse phase protein array (RPPA) is a high-throughput antibody-based technique with the procedures similar to that of Western blots. Proteins are extracted from tumor tissue or cultured cells, denatured by SDS, printed on nitrocellulose-coated slides followed by antibody probe.
What are the advantages of RPPA? # Inexpensive, high-throughput method utilizing automation for increased quality and reliability Sample preparation requirements are similar to that of Western blots Complete assay requires only 40 microliters of each sample for 150 antibodies Robust quantification due to serial dilution of samples Here, I compare the differentially expressed genes based on the patients&amp;rsquo; status(aLive or dead) and their associated functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional analysis</title>
      <link>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-09-14-functional-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-09-14-functional-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Here mainly introduce over representation analysis(ORA), gene set enrichment analysis(GSEA) and gene set variation analysis(GSVA).
1. Over representation analysis(ORA) Hypergeometric test is a statistical method used to determine if the frequency of a specific subset in a sample significantly deviates from what would be expected under random sampling. To be specific, we classify the genes we’ve selected to see which ones have functions relevant to our research. Then, we conduct a test and use the p-value to determine if the association is random or significant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to PCA</title>
      <link>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-09-14-introduction-to-pca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xiwen514.github.io/post/2023-09-14-introduction-to-pca/</guid>
      <description>PCA is an unsupervised analysis that reflects the true trend of the data itself.
PCA is one of the dimension reduction methods.The purpose of PCA (Principal Component Analysis) is to transform the original data into a new coordinate system, where the variance of the data along the axes is maximized. The first principal component (PC1) represents the direction of the greatest variance in the data, while the second principal component (PC2) is orthogonal to PC1 and represents the direction of the second greatest variance, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
